<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Charming Cairo</string>
    <!--  The names of Categories  -->
    <string name="category_pharaonic">Pharaonic Places</string>
    <string name="category_historical">Historical Places</string>
    <string name="category_parks">Parks</string>
    <string name="category_Hotels">Hotels</string>
<!-- Pharaonic Attractions in Cairo -->
    <!--  Giza Pyramids details -->
    <string name="pyramids_title">The Three Pyramids of Giza</string>
    <string name="pyramids_description">They are a defining symbol of Egypt and
        the last of the ancient Seven Wonders of the World.
   Their names are: Khufu, Khafre, and Menkaure—correspond to the kings for whom they were built. </string>
    <string name="pyramids_site_work_hours">Open from 8.00 am to 4.00 pm everyday</string>
    <!--  Solar Boats Museum details -->
    <string name="Solar_Boat_title">The Solar Boats Museum</string>
    <string name="Solar_Boat_description">Also named Khufu\'s boat. It was constructed next to the Great Pyramid of Khufu.
        The Solar boats of ancient Egyptians consist of large ships that were made out of cedar wood.
        Probably these boats were manufactured to be used in the funerary rituals of the King and
        maybe some of his royal family members. </string>
    <string name="solar_boats_museum_work_hours">Open from 8.30 am to 4.00 pm everyday</string>
    <!--  Sphinx details -->
    <string name="Sphinx_title">Great Sphinx of Giza</string>
    <string name="Sphinx_description"> (Arabic: Abū al-Haul, literally: Father of Dread),
        is a limestone statue of a reclining sphinx,
        a mythical creature with the body of a lion and the head of a human.
        it stands on the Giza Plateau on the west bank of the Nile in Giza, Egypt, near Khafre Pyramid.</string>
    <string name="Sphinx_work_hours">Open from 8.00 am to 4.00 pm everyday</string>

    <!--  Sound and light shows details -->
    <string name="s_l_shows_title">Giza Pyramids Sound and Light Shows</string>
    <string name="s_l_shows_description"> It is a magnificent show that brings creatively to life the rule of ancient Egyptians.
        For an hour, you enjoy the sound and light show near the pyramids and the Sphinx.
        The history is re-told by the Sphinx, telling you the most ancient secrets of the world.</string>
    <string name="s_l_shows_work_hours">Open from 7.00 pm to 8.30 pm everyday</string>
    <string name="s_l_shows_contact">33857320(+202)</string>
    <!-- Pyramid of Djoser details -->
    <string name="Pyramid_of_Djoser_title">Pyramid of Djoser</string>
    <string name="Pyramid_of_Djoser_description">The Pyramid of Djoser or Zoser, or step pyramid is an archeological remain in the Saqqara necropolis,
        Egypt, northwest of the city of Memphis. This first Egyptian pyramid consisted of six mastabas (of decreasing size)
        built atop one another. It is seven levels high and four-sided.</string>
    <string name="Pyramid_of_Djoser_work_hours">Open from 8.00 am to 5 pm everyday</string>
    <!-- Pharaonic village details -->
    <string name="Pharaonic_village_title">The Pharaonic village</string>
    <string name="Pharaonic_village_description">The Pharaonic Village is Egypt\'s historic park.
        It\'s a unique place where Egypt\'s entire history is explained in 2 to 3 hours including
        our ancient history as well as our modern history. In this village you are transported by floating amphitheaters, and a hundred actors and
        actresses demonstrate scenes from ancient Egypt (Papyrus making, sculpting, home building….etc.).</string>
    <string name="Pharaonic_village_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 8.30 pm everyday</string>
    <string name="Pharaonic_village_contact">35722533(+202)</string>
    <!-- Egyptian Museum details -->
    <string name="Egyptian_Museum_title">The Egyptian Museum</string>
    <string name="Egyptian_Museum_description">The Museum of Egyptian Antiquities, known commonly as the Egyptian Museum,
        in Cairo, Egypt, is home to an extensive collection of ancient Egyptian antiquities.
        It has 120,000 items. It houses the world\’s largest collection of Pharaonic antiquities. </string>
    <string name="Egyptian_Museum_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 7.00 pm everyday</string>
    <string name="Egyptian_Museum_contact">25794596(+202)</string>
    <!-- Papyrus Egypt Museum details -->
    <string name="Papyrus_Egypt_Museum_title">The Papyrus Egypt Museum</string>
    <string name="Papyrus_Egypt_Museum_description"> Discover in the Papyrus Museum around 300 fascinating objects from
        the Department of Papyri as permanent exhibits. Papyrus in Arabic is pronounced Al-Bardy. </string>
    <string name="Papyrus_Egypt_Museum_work_hours">Open from 8.00 am to 6.00 pm everyday</string>
    <string name="Papyrus_Egypt_Museum_contact">33826935(+202)</string>

<!-- Hotels in Cairo-->
    <!-- Four Seasons Hotel Cairo details -->
    <string name="Four_Seasons_Hotel_title">Four Seasons Hotel Cairo</string>
    <string name="Four_Seasons_Hotel_description"> Four Seasons Hotel Cairo At Nile Plaza offers guests a convenient base when visiting Cairo.
        It provides 5-star accommodation with air-conditioned rooms.
        Providing views of Nile River, it is an ideal place to stay for those wanting to discover local attractions in Cairo.</string>
    <string name="Hotel_work_hours">You can make reservations from their website.</string>
    <string name="Four_Seasons_Hotel_contact">(+202) 2791-7000</string>
    <!-- The Nile Ritz-Carlton Hotel details -->
    <string name="Nile_Ritz_Carlton_Hotel_title">The Nile Ritz-Carlton Hotel Cairo</string>
    <string name="Nile_Ritz_Carlton_Hotel_description"> Overlooking the Nile River, the hotel continues along the path of decadence with 5-star
        amenities including an Olympic-sized pool, a rooftop lounge, spacious accommodations with river and museum views,
        a relaxing spa and a tempting patisserie.</string>
    <string name="Nile_Ritz_Carlton_Hotel_contact">(+202)25778899</string>
    <!-- JW Marriott Hotel Cairo details -->
    <string name="JW_Marriott_Hotel_Cairo_title">JW Marriott Hotel Cairo</string>
    <string name="JW_Marriott_Hotel_Cairo_description">It offers luxury five-star accommodation, award-winning service,
         a prime location in the city\'s Heliopolis district, luxurious marble bathrooms, complimentary Wi-Fi,
        many on-site restaurants, soothing on-site spa and an exhilarating water park.</string>
    <string name="JW_Marriott_Hotel_Cairo_contact">(+202)24115588</string>
    <!-- Dusit Thani LakeView Cairo Hotel details -->
    <string name="Dusit_Thani_LakeView_title">Dusit Thani LakeView Cairo Hotel</string>
    <string name="Dusit_Thani_LakeView_description">It is an oasis of greenery and lakes in the heart of New Cairo.
        Infused with traditional Thai design and offering genuine Thai hospitality, Dusit Thani brings a taste of Thailand
        to the centre of Egypt.</string>
    <string name="Dusit_Thani_LakeView_contact">(+202)2614 0000</string>
    <!-- Sofitel Cairo hotel details -->
    <string name="Sofitel_Cairo_title">Sofitel Cairo Nile El Gezirah Hotel</string>
    <string name="Sofitel_Cairo_description"> A 5-star luxury hotel on the Nile.
        Includes stunning ballroom perfect for weddings, and flexible meeting rooms, vibrant restaurants,
        gaze at breathtaking Nile views. Drift in an infinity pool which seems to spill into the river.
    A haven in the center of Cairo where you are made to feel at home.</string>
    <string name="Sofitel_Cairo_contact">(+202)27373737</string>
    <!-- Fairmont Nile City hotel details -->
    <string name="Fairmont_Nile_City_title">Fairmont Nile City Hotel</string>
    <string name="Fairmont_Nile_City_description">It offers sweeping panoramas of the Nile River,
        and views of the Pyramids in the distance, rooftop poolside sky bar, and truly indulgent, full-service treatments at their
        Willow Stream Spa, outdoor space dedicated for meetings and conventions, comprising of 10 meeting rooms including a ballroom. </string>
    <string name="Fairmont_Nile_City_contact">(+202)24619494</string>
    <!--  Kempinski Nile Hotel details -->
    <string name="Kempinski_title"> Kempinski Nile Hotel</string>
    <string name="Kempinski_description">The ultimate attention to detail, a charming greeting and a row of familiar
        smiles welcoming you. Set in the heart of the city, in the bustling Garden City district and on the banks of the River Nile,
        Kempinski Nile Hotel is a boutique property. It helps you make the most of your stay by offering the services you need,
        the amenities you expect, and the extras you deserve.  </string>
    <string name="Kempinski_contact">(+202)27980000</string>
    <!--  MENA HOUSE Hotel details -->
    <string name="MENA_HOUSE_title">MENA HOUSE Hotel </string>
    <string name="MENA_HOUSE_description">Surrounded by 40 acres of verdant green gardens, this palatial hotel is located in
        the shadows of the Great Pyramids of Giza in Cairo. The royal history of the hotel is reflected in luxurious interiors
        that are embellished with exquisite antiques, handcrafted furniture, original work of arts and magnificent antiques that
        are rarely found in luxury hotels. Mena House has played host to kings and emperors, Heads of State and celebrities. </string>
    <string name="MENA_HOUSE_contact">(+202)33773222</string>
    <!--  Sheraton Cairo Hotel details -->
    <string name="Sheraton_title">Sheraton Cairo Hotel </string>
    <string name="Sheraton_description">With its cosmopolitan modern adjoining towers, Sheraton Cairo Hotel and Casino stands as one of
        Cairo\'s landmarks. The Hotel offers a wide range of dining outlets that suits all tastes with the warmth of the oriental
        hospitality. It perfectly suits family vacation, leisure, business, weddings, meetings and seminars.  </string>
    <string name="Sheraton_contact">(+202)33369700</string>

<!-- National Parks in Cairo -->

    <!--  International Park details -->
    <string name="International_Park_title">International Park </string>
    <string name="International_Park_description">This park has International in its name because some of its flowers, trees,
        and animals originate from different countries around the world. It offers a train ride where visitors can explore its
        different parts within 15 minutes. There is also a theatre inside the park as well as a mini zoo whose
        museum contains some mummified bodies and skeletons of animals with a small board of information for each.</string>
    <string name="International_Park_work_hours">Open from 8.00 am to 11.00 pm everyday</string>
    <string name="International_Park_contact">(+202)23826579</string>
    <!--  Al Horreya Garden details -->
    <string name="Al_Horreya_Garden_title">Al Horreya Garden </string>
    <string name="Al_Horreya_Garden_description">Al Horreya, means freedom in Arabic.
        Al Horreya Garden is known for its unique eleven statues of very important
        figures who had significant impact and positive change in their countries.
     Its eleven statues are for some great people from Egypt, Mexico, Ecuador, Venezuela, and other Latin-American countries.</string>
    <string name="Al_Horreya_Garden_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 7.00 pm everyday</string>
    <!-- Aquarium Grotto Garden details -->
    <string name="Aquarium_Grotto_Garden_title">Aquarium Grotto Garden </string>
    <string name="Aquarium_Grotto_Garden_description"> Unique for its architectural beauty, the garden’s formations are made of clay
        to look like fish gills. The Aquarium Grotto Garden has many underground grottoes that used to host various unique types of
        fish from the Nile and other places. Although the number of fish has decreased and some of the grottoes lie empty,
        the garden still hosts some rare fish that are worth watching.</string>
    <string name="Aquarium_Grotto_Garden_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 4.30 pm everyday except Tuesday</string>
    <string name="Aquarium_Grotto_Garden_contact">(+2)0109 159 3825</string>
    <!-- Al-Andalus Garden details -->
    <string name="Al_Andalus_Garden_title">Al-Andalus Garden </string>
    <string name="Al_Andalus_Garden_description"> It has originally been designed to be part of the royal mansion of Khedive Ismail,
        the Garden is unique for the Andalusian-architectural style.
        This can be seen in the design of the entrance as well as the Andalusian-styled arches.
    A walk through nature with a breathtaking Nile view.</string>
    <string name="Al_Andalus_Garden_work_hours">Open from 8.00 am to 12.30 am everyday </string>
    <string name="Al_Andalus_Garden_contact">(+2)0100 104 1521</string>
    <!-- Japanese Garden details -->
    <string name="Japanese_Garden_title">Japanese Garden </string>
    <string name="Japanese_Garden_description">It was built to represent cultures of the East. It is most famous for its unique statues.
        For example, more than 30 Buddha statues and three statues of elephants adorn the garden.
        A lake there contains a statue of the three wise monkeys.
        Along with the statues, the garden also has a promenade flanked by lanterns, a tall pagoda (a Buddhist temple). </string>
    <string name="Japanese_Garden_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 9.00 pm everyday </string>
    <string name="Japanese_Garden_contact">(+2)0127 041 8322</string>
    <!-- Orman Garden details -->
    <string name="Orman_Garden_title">Orman Garden </string>
    <string name="Orman_Garden_description">Orman, Turkish for the forest. Brought from different parts of the world including Europe and China,
        this garden used to host more than 150 types of flowers and over 500 kinds of rare plants.
        This makes the garden a perfect host for its famous yearly spring festival which attracts visitors during March and April.
        The garden also has a pond with a wooden bridge that stretches over it. </string>
    <string name="Orman_Garden_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 4.00 pm everyday </string>
    <string name="Orman_Garden_contact">(+2)0109 686 2279</string>
    <!-- Family Park details -->
    <string name="Family_Park_title">Family Park </string>
    <string name="Family_Park_description">The Family Park is one of Cairo’s newest parks.
        Activities inside the park can be categorized into two groups: educational and entertaining.
        An educational center has buildings that look like Bibliotheca Alexandria, the Giza Zoo, and the Martial Museum.
        There are also several theaters. In addition, the park displays various infotainment movies in its 3D cinema.
        On the entertainment side, the park has its own mini zoo and safari plaza.</string>
    <string name="Family_Park_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 10.00 pm everyday </string>
    <string name="Family_Park_contact">(+2)0102 738 3885</string>
    <!-- Al-Azhar Park details -->
    <string name="Al_Azhar_Park_title">Al-Azhar Park </string>
    <string name="Al_Azhar_Park_description">Al-Azhar Park is one of Cairo’s largest parks as it covers a space of 80 acres.
     Its position over a hill gives its visitors a magnificent view of Cairo. The green park has several fountains and restaurants
        where visitors can enjoy the natural beauty and the breathtaking views of Cairo.</string>
    <string name="Al_Azhar_Park_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 10.00 pm everyday </string>
    <string name="Al_Azhar_Park_contact">(+202)25103868</string>
    <!-- Safari Park details -->
    <string name="Safari_Park_title">Safari Park </string>
    <string name="Safari_Park_description">This is a very suitable park for family outings.
        It is the second largest park after Al-Azhar Park, which is designed in the country style.
        It has a Romanian theatre, puppet show, artificial lake, as well as a number of restaurants and cafeterias. </string>
    <string name="Safari_Park_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 11.00 pm everyday </string>

    <!-- Historical Places in Cairo -->
    <!-- Citadel of Salah Ed_Din details -->
    <string name="citadel_of_salah_ed_din_title">Cairo Citadel of Salah Ed-Din </string>
    <string name="citadel_of_salah_ed_din_description">Cairo Citadel is a medieval Islamic fortification in Cairo, Egypt.
        The location, on Mokattam hill near the center of Cairo, was once famous for its fresh breeze and grand views of the city.
        It is now a preserved historic site, with mosques and museums.  </string>
    <string name="citadel_of_salah_ed_din_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 4.00 pm everyday </string>
    <string name="citadel_of_salah_ed_din_contact">(+202)25121735</string>
    <!-- The Great Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha details -->
    <string name="Mosque_of_Muhammad_Ali_title">The Great Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha</string>
    <string name="Mosque_of_Muhammad_Ali_description">The Great Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha or Alabaster Mosque is a mosque
        situated in Cairo Citadel of Salah Ed-Din. Situated on the summit of the citadel, this Ottoman mosque,
        the largest to be built in the first half of the 19th century, is, with its animated silhouette and twin minarets,
        the most visible mosque in Cairo.  </string>
    <!-- Muhammad Ali Palace and Museum details -->
    <string name="muhammad_ali_palace_title">Muhammad Ali Palace and Museum </string>
    <string name="muhammad_ali_palace_description">Also known as The Manial Palace and Museum, is a former Ottoman dynasty era palace
        and grounds on Rhoda Island on the Nile. The palace and estate has been preserved as an Antiquities Council directed
        historic house museum and estate, reflecting the settings and lifestyle of the late 19th- and early 20th-century Egyptian
        royal prince and heir apparent. The residence compound, composed of five separate and distinctively styled buildings,
        is surrounded by Persian gardens within an extensive English Landscape garden estate park, along a small branch of the Nile. </string>
    <string name="muhammad_ali_palace_work_hours">Open from 9.00 am to 4.00 pm everyday </string>
    <string name="muhammad_ali_palace_contact">(+202)23687495</string>
    <!-- The palace of Baron Empain details -->
    <string name="The_palace_of_Baron_title">The palace of Baron Empain </string>
    <string name="The_palace_of_Baron_description">The Baron Empain Palace (Arabic: "Qasr el Baron"), is a distinctive and historic Indian-inspired mansion
        in Heliopolis, a suburb northeast of central Cairo, Egypt. Designed by a French architect for the Baron Empain.
        Its main tower - in which Empain had his rooms - is said to have been built on a revolving base to allow a 360-degree
        view and constant sunlight. </string>
    <string name="The_palace_of_Baron_work_hours">A visit needs a permission from the Ministry of Culture </string>
    <string name="The_palace_of_Baron_contact">(+2)010 956 307 55</string>
    <!-- Khan El-Khalili details -->
    <string name="Khan_El_Khalili_title">Khan El-Khalili </string>
    <string name="Khan_El_Khalili_description">Khan el-Khalili is a major souk (Arabic bazaar) in the Islamic district of Cairo.
        The bazaar district is one of Cairo\'s main attractions for tourists and Egyptians alike.
        Some portions of it still display the original Mamluk style architecture, which featured great archways
        and vaulted ceilings. Shops typically sell souvenirs, antiques and jewellery. In addition to shops, there are several
        coffeehouses, generally small and quite traditional, serving Arabic coffee.
    </string>
    <string name="Khan_El_Khalili_work_hours">Most shops are open from 10 am to 1 am everyday. </string>
    <!-- Cairo Tower details -->
    <string name="Cairo_tower_title">Cairo Tower </string>
    <string name="Cairo_tower_description"> The Cairo Tower is a free-standing concrete tower located in Cairo, Egypt.
 One of Cairo\'s well-known modern monuments. Its partially open lattice-work design is intended to evoke a pharaonic lotus plant,
        an iconic symbol of Ancient Egypt. The tower is crowned by a circular observation deck and a rotating restaurant
        with a view over greater Cairo. One rotation takes approximately 70 minutes. </string>
    <string name="Cairo_tower_work_hours"> Open from 9.00 am to 1.00 am everyday</string>
    <string name="Cairo_tower_contact">(202)27365112</string>
    <!-- Ibn_Tulun Mosque details -->
    <string name="Ibn_Tulun_Mosque_title">The Mosque of Ibn Tulun </string>
    <string name="Ibn_Tulun_Mosque_description">(In Arabic: Masjid Ibn Tulun) It is the oldest mosque in the city
        surviving in its original form, and is the largest mosque in Cairo in terms of land area.
        The mosque was commissioned by Ahmad ibn Tulun, the Turkic Abbassid governor of Egypt from
        868–884 whose rule was characterized by de facto independence.
        The minaret of the Mosque is a famous Cairo landmark, though completely unique in its design.
    </string>
    <string name="Ibn_Tulun_Mosque_work_hours"> Open from 9.00 am to 7.00 pm everyday</string>
    <!-- Mosque of Sultan Hassan details -->
    <string name="sultan_Hassan_Mosque_title">The Mosque of Sultan Hassan </string>
    <string name="sultan_Hassan_Mosque_description">The Mosque-School of Sultan Hassan is a massive mosque and school located in the Old city of Cairo,
        it was built during the Mamluk Islamic era in Egypt. At the time of construction the mosque was considered
        remarkable for its fantastic size and innovative architectural components. Commissioned by Sultan an-Nasir Hassan.
        The Mosque of Sultan Hassan is one of the largest mosques in the world, It is known for its work of art building and
        it is the only instance of chinoiserie in Mamluk architecture.
    </string>
    <string name="sultan_Hassan_Mosque_work_hours"> Open from 9.00 am to 5.00 pm everyday</string>
</resources>
